NIMA GOZALPOUR

(+98) 912 296 7907

nimagozalpour@gmail.com

Tehran, Iran

https://nimagozalpour.github.io

PROFILE STATEMENT

Graduate of bachelor's degree in Electronic Engineering and three and a half years of academic experience in the field of Artificial Intelligence. Greatly passionate to apply state-of-the-art technology to real-life and academic problems. Skilled in **Neural Networks**, **Deep Learning**, **Computer Vision**, **Machine Learning**, and **Evolutionary Algorithms**. Currently, I am working on the enhancement of **Reinforcement Learning** in terms of speed by utilizing Deep Learning techniques.

EDUCATION

B.Sc.

K.N. Toosi. University of Technology, Tehran, Iran
Electronic Engineering

Sept. 2012 – Jan. 2018

GPA: 15.45/20 (3.18/4)

Thesis: "Stock Market Price Forecasting by Intelligent Systems"

Supervisor: Prof. M. Teshnehlab

Pre-University

Allame Amini High school, Tehran, Iran

Mathematics and Physics

Sept. 2011 - June 2012

GPA: 18.63/20.00

High School Diploma

Allame Amini High school, Tehran, Iran

Mathematics and Physics

Sept. 2008 - June 2011

GPA: 18.70/20.00

HONORS AND AWARDS

Ranked 1313 Sept. 2012

In the nationwide universities entrance exam among more than 260000 participants in Iran

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant in Systems and Networks Lab, K.N. Toosi University of Technology Supervisor: Prof. A. Ghasemi July 2018 – Apr. 2019

Forming networks using PSO, GA and TLBO evolutionary algorithms with respect to the network algebraic connectivity (Fielder value).

Research Assistant in Intelligent Systems Lab, K.N. Toosi University of Technology

Supervisor: Prof. M. Teshnelab

Feb. 2017 - Mar. 2018

Working on various problems with deep neural network and evolutionary algorithms

Research Assistant in Computer Architecture Lab, Tehran University

Supervisor: Prof. O. Fatemi

Feb. 2016 - Sept. 2016

Working on implementation of Analog and digital parts of a heart pressure monitor device.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

K.N. Toosi University of Technology, Tehran, Iran **Teaching Assistant**

➤ Neural Networks Fall 2017, Instructor: Prof. M. Teshnelab

Computer Architecture Spring 2017 Instructor: Prof. M. Dehyadegari

> Fundamental of Computer Programming Spring 2016, Spring 2017, Spring 2018, Spring 2019 Instructor: Prof. C. Dadkhah

Amirkabir University of Technology, Tehran, Iran

Lecturer, Speech Processing Research Lab

➤ Introduction to Deep Neural Networks Workshop

Summer 2018

PUBLICATIONS

- + Nima Gozalpour, Mohammad Teshnelab, "Forecasting Stock Market Price Using Deep Neural Networks". 7th Iranian Joint Congress on Fuzzy and Intelligent Systems (CFIS), Iran, 2019.
- + Mohammadreza Abolghasemi, **Nima Gozalpour**, Amirhossein Nikoofard, Abdorasoul Ghasemi, "Interdependent Network Formation Game Using TLBO Algorithm". 27th Iranian Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE), Iran, 2019.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Malaria Detection

Classification of infected and uninfected cell images with convolutional neural network and various classifiers, 2019.

AI Plays Ping-Pong

2D ping-pong game in python that the racket is controlled by a neural network in which a genetic algorithm optimizes the weights of the neural network, 2018.

Cracking CAPTCHA Images

Cracking CAPTCHA images of the main Iranian bank and a mobile operator with histogram, morphology filters and softmax classifier, 2018.

Creating a Data Set for CAPTCHA Images

A Google extension for saving a particular image of a web-page and reloading it for several times to achieve various CAPTCHA Images, 2018.

Number Recognition

Classification of MNIST data set with auto-encoder and softmax, 2017.

Selected Codes of Projects are available in my GitHub.

RELATED COURSES

K.N. Toosi University of Technology

Fundamental of Computer Programming (18.25/20), Calculus I (17.5/20), Statistics and Probability (16.2/20), Differential Equations (16.5/20), Logic Circuits (18.25/20), Computer Architecture (17.25/20), Digital Systems II embedded systems (15.1/20), Neural Networks (16.75/20), Thesis (19/20)

Coursera

- Machine Learning by Andrew Ng
- Data Science Math Skills by Daniel Egger
- Algorithms, Part I by Robert Sedgewick and Kevin Wayne

LANGUAGES

English: Fluent, IELTS (Overall band score: 7) (R:8 — L:7 — W:5.5 — S:6.5)

Persian: Native Language **Turkish**: Native Language

COMPUTER SKILLS

Programming: Python, MATLAB, Java, C

Machine Learning: Tensorflow, Keras, Scikit-learn, NumPy

Web Technologies: HTML, CSS, JavaScript **Document Preparation:** LATEX, Microsoft word

REFERENCES

Dr. M. Teshnehlab, Professor

Electrical Engineering

K.N. Toosi University of Technology

Phone: (+98) 21 8406 2323

Email: teshnehlab@eetd.kntu.ac.ir

Dr. Amirhossein Nikoofard, Assistant Professor

Electrical Engineering

K.N. Toosi University of Technology

Phone: (+98) 21 8406 2209

Email: a.nikoofard@eetd.kntu.ac.ir